{
    "quizId" : "111111",
    "quizTitle" : "MyQuiz",
    "quizDomain" :  {
        "domainId":119,
        "domain" : "Operating Systems"
},
    "quizDuration" : "1",
    "questions" : [
       
        
        {
            "questionId" : "782",
            "question" : "The content of the matrix Need is ______  ",
            "difficulty" : "HARD",
            "correctOption" : "Max – Allocation",
             "domain" : {
                           "domainId":119,
                           "domain" : "Operating Systems"
            },
            "option1" : "Allocation – Available",
            "option2" : "Max – Available",
            "option3" : "Max – Allocation",
            "option4" : "Allocation – Max"
        },
        
       {
            "questionId" : "783",
            "question" : "One problem with the global replacement algorithm is that ____________",
            "difficulty" : "HARD",
            "correctOption" : "a process cannot control its own page – fault rate",
             "domain" : {
                           "domainId":119,
                           "domain" : "Operating Systems"
            },
            "option1" : "it is very expensive",
            "option2" : "many frames can be allocated to a process",
            "option3" : "only a few frames can be allocated to a process",
            "option4" : "a process cannot control its own page – fault rate"
        },
        
       
        
        {
            "questionId" : "785",
            "question" : "When several processes access the same data concurrently and the outcome of the execution depends on the particular order in which the access takes ",
            "difficulty" : "HARD",
            "correctOption" : "race condition",
             "domain" : {
                           "domainId":119,
                           "domain" : "Operating Systems"
            },
            "option1" : "race condition",
            "option2" : "essential condition",
            "option3" : "critical condition",
            "option4" : "Dynamic condition"
        },
        
        {
            "questionId" : "786",
            "question" : "paging is ___",
            "difficulty" : "HARD",
            "correctOption" : "is a method of memory allocation by which the program is subdivided into equal portions, or pages and core is subdivided into equal portions or blocks",
             "domain" : {
                           "domainId":119,
                           "domain" : "Operating Systems"
            },
            "option1" : "is a method of memory allocation by which the program is subdivided into equal portions, or pages and core is subdivided into equal portions or blocks",
            "option2" : "consists of those addresses that may be generated by a processor during execution of a computation",
            "option3" : "allows multiple programs to reside in separate areas of core at the time",
            "option4" : "is a method of allocating processor time"
        },

       {
            "questionId" : "787",
            "question" : "If the displayed system time and date is wrong, you can reset it using",
            "difficulty" : "HARD",
            "correctOption" : "Control panel",
            "domain" : {
                           "domainId":119,
                           "domain" : "Operating Systems"
            },
            "option1" : "Write",
            "option2" : "Calendar",
            "option3" : "Write file",
            "option4" : "Control panel"
        },

        {
            "questionId" : "788",
            "question" : "Thread synchronization is required because _______",
            "difficulty" : "HARD",
            "correctOption" : "all of the mentioned",
             "domain" : {
                           "domainId":119,
                           "domain" : "Operating Systems"
            },
            "option1" : "all threads of a process share the same address space",
            "option2" : "all threads of a process share the same global variables",
            "option3" : "all threads of a process can share the same files",
            "option4" : "all of the mentioned"
        },

       {
            "questionId" : "789",
            "question" : "A process is thrashing if ________",
            "difficulty" : "HARD",
            "correctOption" : "it is spending more time paging than executing",
              "domain" : {
                           "domainId":119,
                           "domain" : "Operating Systems"
            },
            "option1" : "it is spending more time paging than executing",
            "option2" : "page fault occurs",
            "option3" : "it is spending less time paging than executing",
            "option4" : "swapping can not take place"
        },

       {
            "questionId" : "790",
            "question" : " In most cases, if a process is sent a signal while it is executing a system call ____________",
            "difficulty" : "HARD",
            "correctOption" : "the signal has no effect until the system call completes",
             "domain" : {
                           "domainId":119,
                           "domain" : "Operating Systems"
            },
            "option1" : "the system call will continue execution and the signal will be ignored completely",
            "option2" : "the system call is interrupted by the signal, and the signal handler comes in",
            "option3" : "the signal has no effect until the system call completes",
            "option4" : "none of the mentioned"
        },


      {
            "questionId" : "791",
            "question" : " The three ways in which a process responds to a signal are __________",
            "difficulty" : "HARD",
            "correctOption" : "all of the mentioned",
             "domain" : {
                           "domainId":119,
                           "domain" : "Operating Systems"
            },
            "option1" : "ignoring the signal",
            "option2" : "handling the signal",
            "option3" : "performing some default action",
            "option4" : "all of the mentioned"
        },

        {
            "questionId" : "792",
            "question" : "Which of the following page replacement algorithms return the minimum number of page faults?",
            "difficulty" : "HARD",
            "correctOption" : "Optimal page replacement algorithm",
             "domain" : {
                           "domainId":119,
                           "domain" : "Operating Systems"
            },
            "option1" : "LRU replacement algorithm",
            "option2" : "Optimal page replacement algorithm",
            "option3" : "FIFO",
            "option4" : "Counting based replacement"
        },
    
        {
            "questionId" : "793",
            "question" : "consider the following sequence of addresses : 123,215,600,1234,76,96. If page size is 100, then the reference string is?",
            "difficulty" : "HARD",
            "correctOption" : "1,2,6,12,0,0",
             "domain" : {
                           "domainId":119,
                           "domain" : "Operating Systems"
            },
            "option1" : "1,2.6,12",
            "option2" : "12,21,60,123,7,9",
            "option3" : "1,2,6,12,0,0",
            "option4" : "0,2,6,12,0,0"
        },

        {
            "questionId" : "794",
            "question" : "Working set model for page replacement is based on the assumption of ___________",
            "difficulty" : "HARD",
            "correctOption" : "locality",
            "domain" : {
                           "domainId":119,
                           "domain" : "Operating Systems"
            },
            "option1" : "modularity",
            "option2" : "locality",
            "option3" : "globalization",
            "option4" : "random access"
        },

        {
            "questionId" : "795",
            "question" : "What is the main function of the command interpreter?",
            "difficulty" : "HARD",
            "correctOption" : "to get and execute the next user-specified command",
             "domain" : {
                           "domainId":119,
                           "domain" : "Operating Systems"
            },
            "option1" : "to get and execute the next user-specified command",
            "option2" : "to provide the interface between the API and application program",
            "option3" : "to handle the files in operating system",
            "option4" : "none of the mentioned"
        },

        {
            "questionId" : "796",
            "question" : "Which facility dynamically adds probes to a running system, both in user processes and in the kernel?",
            "difficulty" : "HARD",
            "correctOption" : "DTrace",
             "domain" : {
                           "domainId":119,
                           "domain" : "Operating Systems"
            },
            "option1" : "DTrace",
            "option2" : "DLocate",
            "option3" : "DMap",
            "option4" : "DAdd"
        },

        {
            "questionId" : "797",
            "question" : " Which of the following mode is used for opening a file in both reading and writing?",
            "difficulty" : "HARD",
            "correctOption" : "O_RDWR",
             "domain" : {
                           "domainId":119,
                           "domain" : "Operating Systems"
            },
            "option1" : "O_RDONLY",
            "option2" : "O_WRONLY",
            "option3" : "O_RDWR",
            "option4" : "O_WDR"
        },

       {
            "questionId" : "798",
            "question" : " Which directory implementation is used in most Operating System?",
            "difficulty" : "HARD",
            "correctOption" : "Tree directory structure",
             "domain" : {
                           "domainId":119,
                           "domain" : "Operating Systems"
            },
            "option1" : "Single level directory structure",
            "option2" : "Two level directory structure",
            "option3" : "Tree directory structure",
            "option4" : "Acyclic directory structure"
        },

        {
            "questionId" : "799",
            "question" : "Which of the following will determine your choice of systems software for your computer?",
            "difficulty" : "HARD",
            "correctOption" : "Both 1 and 3",
             "domain" : {
                           "domainId":119,
                           "domain" : "Operating Systems"
            },
            "option1" : "Is the applications software you want to use compatible with it ?",
            "option2" : "Is it expensive ?",
            "option3" : "Is it compatible with your hardware ?",
            "option4" : "Both 1 and 3"
        },

       {
            "questionId" : "800",
            "question" : "_______ refers to identifying each user of the system and associating the executing programs with those users",
            "difficulty" : "HARD",
            "correctOption" : "Authentication",
            "domain" : {
                           "domainId":119,
                           "domain" : "Operating Systems"
            },
            "option1" : "One Time passwords",
            "option2" : "Authentication",
            "option3" : "Program Threats",
            "option4" : "Security"
        },

       {
            "questionId" : "801",
            "question" : "Multithreading on a multi : CPU machine ___________",
            "difficulty" : "HARD",
            "correctOption" : "increases concurrency",
              "domain" : {
                           "domainId":119,
                           "domain" : "Operating Systems"
            },
            "option1" : "decreases concurrency",
            "option2" : "increases concurrency",
            "option3" : "doesn't affect the concurrency",
            "option4" : "can increase or decrease the concurrency"
        },

         {
            "questionId" : "802",
            "question" : "Which one of the following is a visual ( mathematical ) way to determine the deadlock occurrence",
            "difficulty" : "HARD",
            "correctOption" : "resource allocation graph",
             "domain" : {
                           "domainId":119,
                           "domain" : "Operating Systems"
            },
            "option1" : "resource allocation graph",
            "option2" : "starvation graph",
            "option3" : "inversion graph",
            "option4" : "none of the mentioned"
        },

    

      
  
       {
            "questionId" : "805",
            "question" : " * and ? cannot match ____",
            "difficulty" : "HARD",
            "correctOption" : "ls .???*",
             "domain" : {
                           "domainId":119,
                           "domain" : "Operating Systems"
            },
            "option1" : "/",
            "option2" : "$",
            "option3" : "ls .???*",
            "option4" : "ls * "
        },

        {
            "questionId" : "806",
            "question" : "Which command is used to copy all files having the string chap and any two characters after that to the progs directory?",
            "difficulty" : "HARD",
            "correctOption" : "cp chap?? progs",
             "domain" : {
                           "domainId":119,
                           "domain" : "Operating Systems"
            },
            "option1" : "cp chap?? progs",
            "option2" : "cp chap* progs",
            "option3" : "cp chap?? /progs/*",
            "option4" : "cp chap[12] /progs/*.*"
        },


     
       
        {
            "questionId" : "809",
            "question" : " Which command prints the accumulated user and system times for processes run from the shell?",
            "difficulty" : "HARD",
            "correctOption" : "times",
             "domain" : {
                           "domainId":119,
                           "domain" : "Operating Systems"
            },
            "option1" : "time",
            "option2" : "times",
            "option3" : "both time ad times",
            "option4" : "none of the mentioned"
        },
   
       
        {
            "questionId" : "810",
            "question" : "All the users of the system who are not members of a project group are referred to as",
            "difficulty" : "HARD",
            "correctOption" : "Other users",
             "domain" : {
                           "domainId":119,
                           "domain" : "Operating Systems"
            },
            "option1" : "Group users",
            "option2" : "File owner",
            "option3" : "Group owner",
            "option4" : "Other users"
        }
   ]
}